College of Humanities and Social Sciences Records 1913-1999 1960-1989
Carnegie Mellon University
- Departments, This series is arranged in the following Subseries by Department: Economics English History Philosophy Modern Languages Physical Education Political Science Psychology Social Science Statistics Margaret Morrison Carnegie College
  - History
    - History Dept.--Papers--Okezi Tiffani Otovo--"The Union Needs you and You Need the Union: The Role of Southern Black Migrants in the 1925 Pittsburgh Coal Strike", 1996
    - History Dept.--Papers--Kristofer E. Peterson--"Assessment in Pittsburgh Public Schools at the Turn of the Century", 1996
    - History Dept.--Papers--Harriet K. Protos--"Greek-Americans in Pittsburgh: Where Did They Go?", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Margeret Puskar--"Eat You Must: A Study of Cooking and Home Economics in Pittsburgh, 1880-1910", 1995
    - History Dept.--Papers--Jessie Ramey--"Brackenridge Women of the Depression", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Katherine Rashid--"Social and Medical Response to the Pittsburgh Cholera Epidemic of 1832-33", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Andrew Reilly--"The Mechanization of an Artisanal Process in Pittsburgh: Reuben Haley and Ruba Rombic Art Glass", 1995
    - History Dept.--Papers--Rosalyn Rice--"A Study of the Black Families in the Hill District-Pittsburgh, 1880", 1996
    - History Dept.--Papers--Brian D. Robick--"The Roman Catholic Church in Pittsburgh and the Fall of Charles Stuart Parnell", 1996
    - History Dept.--Papers--Bruce Rodgers, Lizabeth Cohen--"Producing Culture: Aspects of Changing Lifestyles and the Transition from Blue to White Collar Economy in Pittsburgh, 1960-1987", date unknown
    - History Dept.--Papers--M. K. Rodgers--"Reading History in the Advertising of the H. J. Heinz Company from 1910 to 1960", 1992
    - History Dept.--Papers--Bob Sabharwal--"A Good Place to Walk Your Dog: The Rise of Shady Side as an Affluent Community Over the Last Twenty-Five Years", 1991
    - History Dept.--Papers--Adam C. Schure--"The Formation of the Butler Pennsylvania Jewish Community", 1991
    - History Dept.--Papers--Leon B. Scoratow--"The Arbiter Ring: the Growth and Decline of the Socialist Labor Movement in the Pittsburgh Jewish Community, 1904-1947", 1996
    - History Dept.--Papers--Anne Short--"The Italian Immigrant Press in Western Pennsylvania", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Ed Slavishak--"To Protect and Serve: The Establishment and Re-Organization of the Carnegie Mellon Campus Security Office, 1960-1970", 1995
    - History Dept.--Papers--Lauren Sroczysnki--"A Loss of Ethnicity: The Polish Community of Pittsburgh in the Twentieth Century", 1992
    - History Dept.--Papers--Jodi Straitiff--"An Examination of Early Twentieth Century Child-Rearing Techniques in Pittsburgh", 1993
    - History Dept.--Papers--Rebecca Tiger--"The Ultimate Defeat: Women Workers in the UE from 1936 to 1952", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Alex Jonisson--"An Examination of the Bull Moose Progressive Movement During the 1912 Presidential Election Race in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania", 1996
    - History Dept.--Papers--Beth Trapani--"Pittsburgh During the Civil War, 1860-1863", 1996
    - History Dept.--Papers--Kerri Ullucci--"Remember Carnegie and Come Armed!: Klansmen’s Rally, Scotsdale, PA, 1923", 1996
    - History Dept.--Papers--Marci Anne Vail--"Race Relations and Liturgy at Holy Rosary Parish in the Homewood Section of Pittsburgh Since 1947", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Christian Viola--"Pittsburgh’s Mayoral Election of 1850", 1996
    - History Dept.--Papers--Eric Weakland--"Dreyfus and the Pittsburgh Catholic: The Forming of a Pittsburgh Perspective", 1992
    - History Dept.--Papers--Jacquelyn Webber--"Living Arrangements of the Elderly in Pittsburgh from 1930 to 1980: A Neighborhood Analysis", date unknown
    - History Dept.--Papers--Anne Whidden--"The Controversy Over Abortion in Pittsburgh, 1970-1974", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Arie M. Winograd--"A Quest for Style: The Origin and Evolution of Aerosol Graffiti Art in New York City", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Leeann Witherspoon--Pittsburgh Department Stores and Women: 1880-1930", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Brian C. R. Zugay--"The Building of the East Liberty Presbyterian Church-Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania-1930-1935", 1991
    - History Dept.--Notes--Misc., date unknown
  - Philosophy
    - Philosophy--"Why Study Philosophy?", date unknown
    - Philosophy--Annual Reports, 1973-1982
    - Philosophy--Visiting Committee, 1976
    - Philosophy--Visiting Committee, 1990
    - Philosophy--Program Reports, 1973-1975
    - Philosophy--Faculty, Staff, Graduate Student List, date unknown
    - Philosophy--Department Statistics, 1985-1986
    - Philosophy--Faculty General Correspondence, 1984
    - Philosophy--Course Offerings, 1974-1976
    - Philosophy--Course Offerings, 1977-1986
    - Philosophy--Course Pack 80-385, date unknown
    - Philosophy--Course Pack 80-385, date unknown[2]
    - Philosophy--Course Pack 80-385, date unknown[3]
    - Philosophy--Graduate Programs, 1993-1996
    - Philosophy--Graduate Program--General Description, date unknown
    - Philosophy--Correspondence--Establishment as Department, 1975
    - Philosophy--Correspondence--Establishment as Department, 1982-1985
    - Philosophy--Schwartz, Thomas, date unknown
    - Philosophy--Newsclippings, Press Releases, 1966-1986
    - Philosophy--Brochures, date unknown
    - Philosophy--Poster, 1998
    - Philosophy--Lecture Poster, date unknown
  - Modern Languages
    - Modern Languages--Activities Report, 1976
    - Modern Languages--Annual Report, 1924-1925
    - Modern Languages--Annual Report, 1925-1926
    - Modern Languages--Annual Report, 1970-1971
    - Modern Languages--Annual Report, 1971-1972
    - Modern Languages--Annual Report, 1972-1973
    - Modern Languages--Annual Report, 1973-1974
    - Modern Languages--Review Committee Report, 1974
    - Modern Languages--Visiting Committee Report, 1979
    - Modern Languages--Visiting Committee Report, 1979[2]
    - Modern Languages--Visiting Committee Report, 1979[3]
    - Modern Languages--Visiting Committee Report, 1979[4]
    - Modern Languages--Visiting Committee Report, 1979[5]
    - Modern Languages--Visiting Committee Correspondence, 1978
    - Modern Languages--Challenge Grant Proposal, 1988
    - Modern Languages--Faculty--Teaching Loads, 1967
    - Modern Languages--Faculty, 1976-1979
    - Modern Languages--Silenieks Evaluation, 1973-1974
    - Modern Languages--Faculty--Teaching Position Inquiries, 1953-1956
    - Modern Languages--Faculty--General Correspondence, 1958-1964
    - Modern Languages--Faculty--General Correspondence, 1966-1968
    - Modern Languages--Student Majors, 1963-1964
    - Modern Languages--Qualifying Exams, 1957-1962
    - Modern Languages--Course Offerings, 1953
    - Modern Languages--Course Offerings, 1961-1962
    - Modern Languages--Course Offerings, 1967
    - Modern Languages--Course Offerings, 1969-1970
    - Modern Languages--Course Offerings, 1975-1978
    - Modern Languages--Course Offerings--Chatam College, 1967-1968
    - Modern Languages--Summer Study, 1974
    - Modern Languages--Language: Summer Inst., 1982
    - Modern Languages--Graduate Program, date unknown
    - Modern Languages--Major Publications List, 1971-1977
    - Modern Languages--Brochure, 1998
    - Modern Languages--Pamphlet--Modern Language Summer Session, 1977
    - Modern Languages--Memoranda, 1977
    - Modern Languages--Memoranda, 1978
    - Modern Languages--Memoranda, 1978[2]
    - Modern Languages--Memoranda, 1979
    - Modern Languages--Articles and Newsclippings, 1953-1962
    - Modern Languages--Memorandum, Newsclippings--Translation Center Study Abroad, date unknown
    - Modern Languages--Brochures--Study Abroad, 1987
    - Modern Languages--Translation and English Language Center--Annual Report, 1976-1977
    - Modern Languages--Translation and English Language Center, 1978
    - Modern Languages--Translation Center--Workshops, 1978
    - Modern Languages--Translation Center--Study/Work-Training Program, 1978
    - Modern Languages--Pamphlets--Translation and English Language Center, date unknown
    - Modern Languages--Translation Center--Newsclippings, Memoranda, date unknown
    - Modern Languages--Translation Center--Memoranda, 1978-1980
    - Modern Languages--Center for the Study of Translation--"Automating Translation in the 1980s", 1979
    - Modern Languages--Center for the Study of Translation, 1980
    - Modern Languages--Center for the Study of Translation--"Scientific Management of the Translation Process", date unknown
  - Physical Education
    - Physical Education (Men)--Memoranda, 1963-1967
    - Physical Education (Women)--Memoranda, 1965-1967
  - Political Science
    - Political Science--Course Descriptions, date unknown
  - Psychology
    - Psychology--Annual Reports, 1915-1924
    - Psychology/Education--Annual Report, 1923-1924
    - Psychology/Education--Annual Report, 1924-1925
    - Psychology/Education--Annual Report, 1925-1926
    - Psychology--Annual Report, 1973-1974
    - Psychology--Annual Report, 1975-1976
    - Psychology--Annual Report, 1976-1977
    - Psychology--Annual Report, 1977-1978
    - Psychology--Annual Report, 1978-1979
    - Psychology--Visiting Committee Report, 1988
    - Psychology--Department Statistics, 1975-1986
    - Psychology--Faculty--Teaching Loads, 1976-1982
    - Psychology--Faculty, 1979
    - Psychology--Faculty--General Correspondence, 1963-1968
    - Psychology--Faculty, 1983
    - Psychology--Faculty--General Correspondence, 1982-1985
    - Psychology--Student Proposals, 1971-1981
    - Psychology--"The Student Document", 1968
    - Psychology--Course Offerings, 1968-1971
    - Psychology--Graduate Programs, 1949-1979
    - Psychology--Graduate Programs, 1978-1979
    - Psychology--Graduate Programs, 1988-1993
    - Psychology--Graduate Committee Handbook, 1961
    - Anderson, John--Geometry Tutor Proposal, 1984
    - Bingham, Walter Van Dyke--"A History of Psychology in Autobiography and Biography", 1952
    - Burstyn, Joan N.--"Catherine Beecher and the Education of American Women", 1972
    - Cleeton, Glen U.--"Making Work Human", 1956
    - Forehand and Moyer--"Teaching by Consortium: A Method for Developing College Programs and Teachers", date unknown
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"The Effect of Simultaneous Visual Stimulation on Absolute Auditory Sensitivity", 1952
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"The Effect of Stimulus Complexity on Discriminative Responses", 1954
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Changes in Distribution of Muscular Tension During Psychomotor Performance", 1958
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Acquisition of Perceptual Responses as a Function of Loading, Location, and Repetition", 1961
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Factorial Structure of Impact and Damage in Light Plane Accidents", 1961
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Impact-Injury Relationships in Light Plane Accidents", 1961
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Perceptual and Motor Skills", 1961
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Prediction of Degree of Injury from Impact and Damage Variables in Light Plane Accidents", 1961
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Psychological Evaluation of Work Capabilities", 1961
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"The Effect of Systematic and Non-Systematic Presentation of Stimuli on Peripheral Visual Acuity", 1962
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Handbook for Aircraft Accident Investigators", 1962
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"New Techniques for Assessing Damage from Accident Investigations", 1962
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"The Effect of Rate of Presentation, Substitution, and Mode of Response in Paired Associate Learning", 1963
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"New Techniques for Assessing Damage from Accident Investigations", 1963
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Perceptual Responses as a Function of the Sequential Properties of Multiple Visual Stimuli", 1963
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Effect of Stimulus Separation on the Perception of Multiple Targets", 1964
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Injury Reduction Trends in Agricultural Aviation", 1964
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Studies in Accident Prevention", 1964
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Effects of Instructions on Damage Estimates from Single Photographs", 1965
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"An Information Processing Analysis of Mental Multiplication", 1966
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Effects of Induced Chunking on Temporal Aspects of Serial Recitation", 1967
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"An Information-Processing Explanation of One-Trial and Incremental Learning", 1967
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Process Models and Stochastic Theories of Simple Concept Formation", 1967
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Similarities in the Cognitive Processes of Monkeys and Man", 1971
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Simulation Models of Learning and Memory", 1972
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"APCOL: A Programming System for Computer Controlled Psychology Laboratories", 1973
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"A Course of Formal Instruction in On-Line Computing at Carnegie Mellon University", 1973
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Color, Form, and Function as Dimensions of Natural Classification: Developmental Changes in Eye Movements, Reaction Time, and Response Strategies", 1975
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Computers: Large-Scale Usage in the Balance", 1975
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Short Term Memory Function in Young Readers", 1975
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Grade Distribution", 1977
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Maximizing the Mini-Uses of On-Line Computers", 1977
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"A Computerized Reference Library Using Zog", 1980
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Grade Inflation: A Case History and Sometime Mystery", date unknown
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Internal Representations of Sequential Concepts", date unknown
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Methods and Models for Task Analysis and Instructional Design", date unknown
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Optimal Policies or Wise Choices? A Critique of Smallwood’s Optimization Procedure", date unknown
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Perceptual Structures and Semantic Relations", date unknown
    - Gregg, Lee W.--"Spatial Concepts, Spacial Names, and the Development of Exocentric Represents", date unknown
    - Goldstein and Korn--"The Social Psychology and Epidemiology of Student Drug Use: A Report on Phase I", 1970
    - Goldstein and Korn--"The Social Psychology and Epidemiology of Student Drug Use: A Report on Phase I", 1970[2]
    - Goldstein and Korn--"Judging the Things to Come: Lessons Learned from Comparisons of Student Drug Use in 1968 and 1970", date unknown
    - Goldstein, Joel W.--"Getting High in High School: The Meaning of Adolescent Drug Use", 1969
    - Hayes, John R.--"Research, Teaching, and Faculty Fate", 1971
    - Kimble, Gregory A.--"A Department Chairperson’s Survival Manual", date unknown
    - Larry, Frank--"Development of I/O Psychology", 1992
    - Moyer, K.E.--"Territorial Aggression: Is This Concept Useful?", 1973
    - Moyer, K.E.--"Internal Impulses to Aggression", 1974
    - Simon, Herbert--"Bibliography", date unknown
    - Sales, Stephan--"Economic Threat as a Determinant of Conversion in Authoritarian and Non-Authoritarian Churches", date unknown
    - Swaney, Joyce Hannah, Carol Janick, Sandra J. Bond, John R. Hayes--"Editing for Comprehension: Improving the Process Through Reading Protocols", 1981
    - Waterman, D.A.--"Serial Pattern Acquisition: A Production System Approach", 1975
    - Waterman, D.A.--"Adaptive Production Systems", 1976
    - Von Mayrhauser, Richard T.--"Making Intelligence Functional: Walter Dill Scott and Applied Psychological Testing in World War I", 1989
    - Von Mayerhauser, Richard T.--"Walking Out at the Walton: Psychological Disunity and Group Tests in April, 1917", 1984
    - Psychology--Cognition Symposium, 1965-1999
    - Psychology--Children’s School, 1974-1984
    - Psychology--Animal Care Facilities, 1978
    - Psychology--Colloquium Series Poster, 1980
    - Psychology--"Lisp" Tutor, 1984-1986
    - Psychology--"Role Models", 1991
    - Psychology--Program Posters, date unknown
    - Psychology--Faculty--General Correspondence, 1979-1985
    - Psychology--Correspondence--Greg, Lee W., 1977-1978
    - Psychology--Memoranda, 1955-1961
    - Psychology--Memoranda, 1963-1967
    - Psychology--Memoranda, 1980-1982
    - Psychology--Brochures, 1954
    - Psychology--Newsclippings, 1980
  - Social Science
    - Social Science--Department Creation, 1976-1978
    - Social Science--Department Objectives/Policies, 1980-1982
    - Social Science--Department Statistics, 1977-1986
    - Political Science--Annual Report, 1974-1975
    - Social Science--Annual Report, 1977-1980
    - Social Science--Visiting Committee Report, 1987-1989
    - Social Science--Visiting Committee, 1987-1989
    - Social Science--Faculty--Teaching Loads, 1976-1983
    - Social Science--Faculty, 1979
    - Social Science--Faculty, 1981-1982
    - Social Science--Recommended Program of Study, 1978
    - Social Science--Undergraduate Programs, 1974
    - Social Science--Course Offerings, date unknown
    - Social Science--Information Systems Program, 1983
    - Social Science--Program in Policy and Applied Social Science Research, 1983
    - Social Science--Course Offerings--Syllabus (88-102), 1985
    - Social Science--Graduate Program--PhD, date unknown
    - Social Science--Graduate Program--SUPA/Social Science PhD, 1982
    - Social Science--Graduate Programs, 1985-1986
    - Social Science--"Research on Computing Environments at Carnegie Mellon University", 1983
    - Social Science--Social Science in Computing--Working Paper Series, 1983-1984
    - Social Science--"Research on Social Aspects of Computing at Carnegie Mellon University", 1983-1984
    - Davis, Otto A. and Holly H. Johnston--"Behavioural Economics in Markets with Imperfect Information: Consumers and Producers Who Learn and Imitate", 1986
    - Social Decision Sciences--Semina, 1988
    - Social Science--Information Systems--Funding Proposal, 1982
    - Social Science--General Correspondence
    - Social Science--Correspondence, 1988
    - Social Science--Correspondence--Crecine, John P., 1978-1986
    - Social Science--Correspondence--Keisler, Charles, 1982-1983
    - Social Science--Correspondence--Larkey, Pat, 1979-1983
    - Social Science--Correspondence--Van Horn, Richard, 1978-1983
    - Social Science--Correspondence--Weber, A. R., 1977-1978
    - Social and Behavioral Science--Program, 1989
  - Statistics
    - Statistics--Annual Report, 1978-1979
    - Statistics--Annual Report, 1981-1982
    - Statistics--Annual Report, 1982-1983
    - Statistics--Visiting Committee, 1989
    - Statistics--Faculty--Teaching Payloads, 1981-1982
    - Statistics--Faculty--General Correspondence, 1980-1989
    - Statistics--Department Statistics, 1975-1985
    - Statistics--Graduate Program, 1968-1986
    - Statistics--Main Operations Research, 1983-1984
    - Statistics--Graduate Program--Brochures/Posters, date unknown
    - Statistics--Newsclips, Memorandum, 1974
    - Moore, David S. and Ingram Olkin--"Statistics: Change and Resources in a Growing Science", 1981
    - Statistics--"Computers in Statistical Research"--Report on Workshop on the Use of Computers in Statistical Research, 1986
    - Statistics--Kadane, J. B., McGuire, T. W., Sanday, P. R., Staelin, R.--"Models of Environmental Effects on the Development of IQ", 1976
    - Statistics--Mann, Nancy--"Why it Happened in Japan and Not in the US", date unknown
  - Margaret Morrison Carnegie College
    - Margaret Morrison Carnegie College--Course Offerings, 1950-1951
    - Margaret Morrison Carnegie College-"A History of the Charter Class of Margaret Morrison Carnegie College", 1959
- Publications/Books, This Series is arranged in the following Subseries by Department of origin: English History
  - English
    - English Usage Drills and Exercises Programmed for the Typewriter, 1968
    - Two Poems--Anne Hayes, 1967
    - Communique: the Communications Design Center Newsletter, Spring 1990
    - Lectures on Modern Novelists, 1963
    - Handbook of English--Austin Wright, 1956
    - Joseph Spence: A Critical Biography--Austin Wright, 1950
    - Bibliographies of Studies in Victorian Literature, 1967
    - Two Hands: Poetry and Fiction, date unknown
    - Gladys Schmitt: Only Human Values--Anita Brostoff--[signed], 1973
    - The Dancer’s Step--Anne Hayes--[signed], 1973
    - Lessons in Russian and Other Reviews--Fred B. Millet, 1965
    - Lessons in Russian and Other Reviews--Fred B. Millet, 1965[2]
    - Ground, May 1970
    - Three Rivers Poetry Journal 9, 1977
    - Three Rivers Poetry Journal 3/4, 1974
    - Three Rivers Poetry Journal 3/4, 1974[2]
    - Grave Old Senior--Fred B. Millet, 1953
    - Apprenticeship--Fred B. Millet, 1954
    - The Year Fourteen--Fred B. Millet, 1955
    - Graduate Student I--Fred B. Millet, 1956
    - Graduate Student II--Fred B. Millet, 1957
    - Portrait of the Teacher as an Artist--James Lord, 1958
    - Student at Arms--Fred B. Millet, 1959
    - From the Mill House Journal--Fred B. Millet, 1960
    - Carnegie Tech--Fred B. Millet, 1961
    - Varieties of Dramatic Experience--Fred B. Millet, 1962
    - Varieties of Dramatic Experience--Fred B. Millet, 1962[2]
    - Proceedings of the Wingspread Conference on the Doctor of Arts Degree, 1970
    - Carnegie Series in English--Lectures on Four of Shakespeare’s History Plays, 1953
    - Carnegie Series in English--Lectures on Four of Shakespeare’s History Plays, 1953[2]
    - Carnegie Series in English--Lectures on Some Modern Poets, 1955
    - Carnegie Series in English--Lectures on Some Modern Poets, 1955[2]
    - Carnegie Series in English--All the King’s Men: A Symposium, 1957
    - Carnegie Series in English--All the King’s Men: A Symposium, 1957[2]
    - Carnegie Series in English--Shakespeare: Lectures on Five Plays, 1958
    - Carnegie Series in English--Shakespeare: Lectures on Five Plays, 1958[2]
    - Carnegie Series in English--Six Novelists, 1959
    - Carnegie Series in English--Six Novelists, 1959[2]
    - Carnegie Series in English--Studies in Faulkner, 1961
    - Carnegie Series in English--Studies in Faulkner, 1961[2]
    - Carnegie Series in English--Studies in Faulkner, 1961[3]
    - Carnegie Series in English--Lectures on Modern Novelists, 1963
    - Carnegie Series in English--"Lovers Meeting" Discussion of Five Plays by Shakespeare, 1964
    - Carnegie Series in English--"Lovers Meeting" Discussion of Five Plays by Shakespeare, 1964[2]
    - Carnegie Series in English--Six Satirists, 1965
    - Carnegie Series in English--Six Satirists, 1965[2]
    - Carnegie Series in English--"Starre of Poets" Discussions of Shakespeare, 1966
    - Carnegie Series in English--"Starre of Poets" Discussions of Shakespeare, 1966[2]
    - Carnegie Series in English--A Modern Miscellany, 1970
    - Carnegie Series in English--A Modern Miscellany, 1970[2]
    - Carnegie Series in English--In Honor of Austin Wright, 1972
    - Carnegie Series in English--In Honor of Austin Wright, 1972[2]
    - Carnegie Series in English--I Could Be Mute: The Life and Work of Gladys Schmitt, 1978
    - Carnegie Series in English--Dramatic Structure in Shakespeare’s Romantic Comedies, 1980
    - English--Poetry--Moorke, Andrea Dubo, 1969
    - English--"The Doctoral of Arts in English", date unknown
    - English--Schmitt, Gladys--Press Clippings, 1968-1972
    - English--Publications--The Student Reading Series Chapbook, 1995-1996
  - History
    - Publications--"Educational Psychology"
    - Publications--"Henry James Psychology of Experience"
    - Publications—"Cognitive Processes in Writing"
    - Publications--"Groups, Leadership, and Men"
    - Publications—"Russia's Educational Heritage"
    - Publications—"Enjoyment of the Arts"
    - Publications—"Executive Ability: Its Discovery and Development"
    - Publications--"Human Nature in the Making"
    - Publications—"Making Work Human"
    - Publications—"Executive Ability: Its Discovery and Development"[2]